An Inventory of the Elbridge Durbrow papers, 1926-1996
Hoover Institution Archives
- Printed material and photocopies, 1969, 1972, 1974-1976, 1978-1980, 1987, undated (Box 53)
- International press summaries, 1979 (Box 53)
- Correspondence, 1947, 1969, 1972, 1979, 1983, 1986, 1988, undated (Box 53)
- Mailgram messages to Ronald Reagan, 1986 (Box 53)
- Memoranda photocopies, 1947, undated. (Box 53)
  Includes information on driving in Paris for all embassy staff
- List of acronyms Durbrow used for filing and organizing his papers, undated (Box 53)
- Durbrow oral history for Eisenhower Library, transcript, 1979 (Box 53)
- The National Archives and Records Service legal agreement form, undated (Box 53)
- Soviet Propaganda Operations, CIA report photocopy, 1978 (Box 53)
- Behind the Headlines broadcast, transcript, 1979 (Box 53)
- "Détente - How Realistic?" by Durbrow, outline, 1975 (Box 53)
- Washington Report of the Air with Durbrow, transcript, 1973 (Box 53)
- Friendship Delegation summary of trip to Taiwan, 1979 (Box 53)
- Drafts by Durbrow, 1941, 1947, 1960, 1967, 1971, 1974-1977, 1979-1980, 1983, undated (Box 53)
  - "The Declaration of Renewed Cold War,", 1971 (Box 53)
  - "Center Left-Wing Coalition Governments?", undated (Box 53)
  - "A New U.S. Strategy for Peace and Freedom,", 1977 (Box 53)
  - "The Unseen Revolution,", 1976 (Box 53)
  - "Détente's Triple Threat,", 1979 (Box 53)
  - "Hot War, Cold War, and Détente,", 1975 (Box 53)
  - "Hanoi's Intensified Aggression - 1959,", 1967 (Box 53)
  - "Principle of Relations with the Non Communist Nations,", 1960 (Box 53)
  - "Operation 'Dezinformatsia',", 1980 (Box 53)
  - "Life in Rome,", 1941 (Box 53)
  - "El Salvador - Another Soviet War of National Liberation,", 1983 (Box 53)
  - "Comments on the International Policy of the Soviet Union in the Second Year of Peace,", 1947 (Box 53)
  - "How to Hunt Relatives in Ticino or A Delightful Visit to Coglio with Bee's Relatives,", 1974 (Box 53)
    Includes color photograph of family on last page
- "Détente as a Weapon of Soviet Policy," by John Eppstein, 1976 (Box 53)
- "Political Violence in Italy," by Angelo M. Codevilla, 1979 (Box 53)
- "Our 'Zero Security' Society," by Senator Orrin G. Hatch, undated (Box 53)
- "Why Should Hanoi Negotiate?" by Durbrow, 1969 (Box 53)
- Clippings, 1961, 1967-1971, 1976, 1979-1982 (Box 54)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1968-1969, 1974, 1978 (Box 54)
- International press summaries, 1966, 1969, 1971, 1980-1982 (Box 54)
- Correspondence, 1967-1968, 1970, 1978-1982, 1984, 1990, undated (Box 54)
- Memorandum, undated (Box 54)
- U.S. government report, 1960, 1970, 1981 (Box 54)
  Includes photocopy
- "Objectives of Soviet Policies and Soviet Propaganda Techniques," speech excerpt, undated (Box 54)
- Aleksey Kosygin speech in Minsk, excerpts, 1968 (Box 54)
- Yale 60th reunion photograph, 1986 (Box 54)
- Certificate of "Officer's Cross of the Order of Polonia Restituta,", 1982 (Box 54)
- Speech outlines by Durbrow, 1971, undated (Box 54)
  - "The Growing Communist Threat,", 1971 (Box 54)
  - "Communist Plans for Victory,", 1971 (Box 54)
  - "Possible Lessons from Prior Negotiations with Communist Regimes,", undated (Box 54)
  - "The Growing Communist Threat,", undated (Box 54)
  - "Problems of Running our Saigon Embassy before Our Forces Entered in Comba,", undated (Box 54)
- National Geographic map of Vietnam and Cambodia, Laos and Eastern Thailand, 1965 (Box 54)
- Map of the Republic of Viet-Nam, undated (Box 54)
- "Laos and Vietnam - The Same War," draft by Durbrow, undated. (Box 54)
  Includes handwritten draft
- "Communist Plans for Victory," outline by Durbrow, 1971 (Box 54)
- "Lest We Forget," by Durbrow, undated (Box 54)
- "Laos and Vietnam - The Same War," by Durbrow, undated (Box 54)
- "The Declaration of Renewed Cold War," by Durbrow, undated (Box 54)
- Clippings, 1968, 1971, 1978, 1982, 1988 (Box 55)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1967-1969, 1975, 1983, 1987-1988 (Box 55)
- Correspondence, 1967, 1968-1971, 1975 (Box 55)
  Includes holiday card from Hoover Institution
- U.S. government report, 1966-1967, 1988 (Box 55)
- University of Miami, Center for Advanced International Studies, staff listing, undated (Box 55)
- Moscow "Old-Timers" meeting documents, 1975 (Box 55)
- USAF photographic map of Vietnam, undated (Box 55)
- Washington Report of the Air broadcasts with Durbrow, transcripts, 1975 (Box 55)
  - "Portugal and the Moscow Blueprint,", 1975 (Box 55)
  - "Peaceful Coexistence and Détente,", 1975 (Box 55)
- Speech outlines by Durbrow, 1972, undated (Box 55)
  - "U.S. Policy in Vietnam,", undated (Box 55)
  - "Communist Plans for Action,", 1972 (Box 55)
  - "Negotiating with Communists,", undated (Box 55)
- Drafts by Durbrow, circa 1968, undated (Box 55)
  - "Deterrence, Verification, First Strike and The Strategic Defense Initiative,", undated (Box 55)
  - "Lest We Forget," 1st-3rd drafts, circa 1968 (Box 55)
  - "Random Comments on Recent Developments" by Durbrow, 1982 (Box 55)
  - "Laos and Vietnam - The Same War" by Durbrow, undated (Box 55)
  - "Hanoi's About Face - 1959" by Durbrow, undated (Box 55)
- Writings by Durbrow, 1982, undated (Box 55)
  - "A New U.S. Strategy for Peace and Freedom,", undated (Box 55)
  - "The Quiet World Revolution,", undated (Box 55)
  - "The Unseen Revolution,", undated (Box 55)
  - "Hot War, Cold War, and Détente,", undated (Box 55)
- Clippings, 1970, 1987-1988. (Box 56)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1971, 1986-1988 (Box 56)
- Correspondence, 1971, 1979 (Box 56)
- U.S. government reports photocopy, 1988 (Box 56)
- "Why Did Eisenhower Not Liberate and Hold Berlin?" drafts by Durbrow, 1971 (Box 56)
  Includes handwritten versions
- Clippings, 1979, 1981-1982, 1985-1987 (Box 57)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1979, 1969, 1981, 1983, 1985-1987 (Box 57)
- Correspondence, 1979 (Box 57)
- Memorandum photocopies, 1946-1947 (Box 57)
- International press summaries, 1979, 1981 (Box 57)
- U.S. government reports, 1968, 1972, 1983-1984 (Box 57)
- Senator Daniel P. Moynihan statement on Soviet electronic eavesdropping, before the Subcommittee on Investigations, Committee on government affairs, December 3, 1985 (Box 57)
- Drafts by Durbrow, undated (Box 57)
  - "Operation 'Dezinformatsia',", undated (Box 57)
  - "Soviet Indirect Aggression: Motives and Methods,", undated (Box 57)
- "Missile Sites in Europe and the Neutron Bomb,", undated (Box 57)
- Sir James Goldsmith address to the Defense Strategy Forum of the National Strategy Information Center, 1984 (Box 57)
- The 20th Congress of the Communist Party of The Soviet Union review report photocopy, 1956 (Box 57)
- "Summary of Diverse Soviet Methods of Operation," speech by Durbrow, undated (Box 57)
- "Decree of Soviet Power," from September 5, 1918, photocopy, 1982 (Box 57)
  Photocopy Translated to English
- "Decree on Red Terror," from September 5, 1918, photocopy, 1982 (Box 57)
- Clippings, 1985-1988 (Box 58)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1985-1988 (Box 58)
- U.S. government reports and photocopies, 1987 (Box 58)
- International press summaries, 1973, 1979-1980 (Box 58)
- Clippings, 1971-1972, 1974-1976, 1980-1981, 1984-1987 (Box 59)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1973, 1978, 1980, 1982, 1984-1986, undated. (Box 59)
- Correspondence, 1971-1976, 1980, 1984-1985. (Box 59)
- Mailgram photocopy, 1975 (Box 59)
- International press summaries, 1974-1976, 1980, 1985 (Box 59)
- Air War College supplement excerpt photocopy, 1967 (Box 59)
- CBS Reports "The Uncounted Enemy: A Vietnam Deception," transcript, January 23, 1982 (Box 59)
- Jerry P. Rosenberg interview with Durbrow, 1975 (Box 59)
- Durbrow oral history conducted by David Mabon for inclusion in the Foreign Relations of the United States, 1958-1960, Volume 1, Vietnam, 1984 (Box 59)
  Includes revised transcript.
- Washington Report of the Air broadcasts with Durbrow, transcripts, 1973, 1975 (Box 59)
- Durbrow's interview for the USAF Oral History Program, 1977 (Box 59)
- USAF Oral History Program access agreement photocopy, 1984 (Box 59)
- "Deterrence, Verification, First Strike and the Strategic Defense Initiative," draft by Durbrow, undated (Box 59)
- "Forgotten Legends: The Brotherhood of Russian Truth," by Natalie Grant, undated (Box 59)
- "Arms Control With or Without Agreements," by Kenneth L. Adelmanm, undated (Box 59)
- "Soviet Organization and Doctrine for Strategic Deception," by Richards J. Heuer, Jr., 1985 (Box 59)
- "The Declaration of Renewed Cold War," by Durbrow, 1971 (Box 59)
- Clippings, 1968-1980, 1982 (Box 60)
- Printed material, 1951, 1961, 1967, 1969-1970, 1973-1974, 1976-1977, 1980, undated (Box 60)
- Correspondence, 1937, 1947, 1962, 1966, 1970-1974, 1976-1977. (Box 60)
- Memoranda photocopies, 1949, 1974, undated (Box 60)
- International press summaries, 1974, 1976 (Box 60)
- U.S. government reports and press releases, 1959, 1973-1974. (Box 60)
- U.S. aid in Cambodia, Laos, and Vietnam, 1974 (Box 60)
- "Support of Continued U.S. Aid to South Vietnam" statement delivered by members of the American Security Council to Senator Daniel Inouye, Chairman of the Foreign Operations Subcommittee of the Senate Appropriations Committee, 1974 (Box 60)
- Washington Report of the Air broadcasts with Durbrow, transcripts, 1973 (Box 60)
  - "In Defense of Ambassador Martin,", 1973 (Box 60)
  - "Cambodia: the Sihanouk Secret,", 1973 (Box 60)
  - "The Middle East War: An Assessment,", 1973 (Box 60)
  - "Despite Allende's Fall Popular Unity Moves Forward,", 1973 (Box 60)
- "Communist Violations of the Paris Agreement," photocopy, 1973 (Box 60)
- "The Issue of Civilian Prisoners in South Viet-Nam," photocopy, 1973 (Box 60)
- Weathermen Underground report photocopy, undated (Box 60)
- The 20th Congress of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union review report photocopy, 1956 (Box 60)
- Prospects for Peace group statement on conditions in South Vietnam photocopy, 1974 (Box 60)
- "Soviet Methods of Operation in Their Long-Range Drive to Attain World Hegemony and the Role of Terrorism Therein," by Durbrow, outline, 1981 (Box 60)
- "Communist Post Vietnam Cease-Fire Plans," by Durbrow, speech outline, undated (Box 60)
- "Chicago to Lisbon," by Durbrow, undated (Box 60)
- "The Singapore Christmas Gift," by Sterling J. Cottrell, undated (Box 60)
- "Churchill Message," unknown author, 1978 (Box 60)
- "Russian Culture and the Purge," chapter XI of memoir draft by Durbrow, circa 1949 (Box 60)
- "Ambassador Martin's Forthright Recommendations," by Durbrow, 1974 (Box 60)
- "Détente - How Realistic?" by Durbrow, undated (Box 60)
- "The Radical Intellectual and U.S. Foreign Policy," by David S. Lichtenstein, undated (Box 60)
- "Highlights of Moscow's Indirect Aggression Offensive Operations," by Durbrow, undated (Box 60)
- "Comments on the International Policy of the Soviet Union in the Second Year of Peace," by Durbrow, 1947 (Box 60)
- Clippings, 1972, 1980, 1982, 1984-1986 (Box 61)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1982, 1985-1986 (Box 61)
- International press summaries, 1979 (Box 61)
- U.S. government report photocopy, 1982 (Box 61)
- Correspondence, 1982 (Box 61)
- Senator Jeremiah Denton statement before the Subcommittee on Security and Terrorism, 1982 (Box 61)
- Mark Felt statement before Senate Subcommittee on Security and Terrorism, 1982 (Box 61)
- "Supporting Charges of Nicaraguan Involvement in El Salvador," photocopy, 1982 (Box 61)
- Clippings, 1971, 1985-1988, 1990 (Box 62)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1961, 1969, 1976, 1985-1989 (Box 62)
- U.S. government report photocopy, 1986 (Box 62)
- Truman by David McCullough, excerpts, 1992 (Box 62)
- Drafts by Durbrow, 1987-1989 (Box 62)
  - "Nicaragua - Another Soviet War of National Liberation,", 1987 (Box 62)
  - "Can Gorbachev Pull It Off? Prospects,", 1988 (Box 62)
  - "The 20th Century's Fortunate Failure ? Leninism,", 1989 (Box 62)
- "Comments on the International Policy of the Soviet Union in the Second Year of Peace," by Durbrow, photocopy, 1947 (Box 62)
- Clippings, 1971-1972, 1974-1978, 1980, 1982, 1988, 1992-1993. (Box 63)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1965, 1968-1973, 1976-1977, 1979, 1982 (Box 63)
- Correspondence, 1972 (Box 63)
- Memorandum, 1971, 1976 (Box 63)
- International press summaries, 1971, 1974-1976, 1981 (Box 63)
- Daniel Ellsberg congressional conference statement, undated (Box 63)
- AFL-CIO Executive Council statement on "Unity and Strength for the Security of Free Europe and World Peace,", 1973 (Box 63)
- New Russia journal, 1939 (Box 63)
  Translated into English
- Drafts by Durbrow, 1973, 1977 (Box 63)
  - "Strategic Implications of Soviet Civil Defense,", 1973 (Box 63)
  - "A New U.S. Strategy For Peace and Freedom,", 1977 (Box 63)
- "The Radical Intellectual and U.S. Foreign" by David S. Lichtenstiein, undated (Box 63)
- "Past and Present CIA Counterintelligence Programs, " by N. Scott Miler, 1976 (Box 63)
- "Soviet 'Peaceful Coexistence' Is Not Western Détente," by Foy D. Kohler, 1974 (Box 63)
- Clippings, 1970, 1972, 1974-1975, 1977-1978, 1981, 1990-1991. (Box 64)
- Correspondence, 1972, 1974-1977, 1981, 1986-1988. (Box 64)
- Mailgrams, 1975-1977, 1981 (Box 64)
  Sent to Presidents Jimmy Carter, Ronald Reagan, and Gerald Ford
- Printed material and photocopies, 1961, 1965, 1969, 1972, 1975, 1980, 1985, 1987-1988. (Box 64)
- International press summaries, 1956, 1981, 1986 (Box 64)
- The 20th Congress of the Communist Party of The Soviet Union review report photocopy, 1956 (Box 64)
- Washington Report of the Air broadcast of interviews with Durbrow, transcripts, 1973-1976 (Box 64)
- The 10 0'clock news, WTTG, segment on "An Appeal to President Carter," transcript, 1977 (Box 64)
- Drafts by Durbrow, 1972, 1977, 1987, undated (Box 64)
  - "Nicaragua ? Another Soviet War of National Liberation,", 1987 (Box 64)
  - "Can We Believe the World Energy Crisis Soon?", undated (Box 64)
  - "A New U.S. Strategy for Peace and Freedom,", 1977 (Box 64)
  - "Peaceful Coexistence: The Cold War's New Name,", 1972 (Box 64)
- "Communist Plans for Victory" by Durbrow, speech outline, undated (Box 64)
- "Soviet Methods of Operation in Their Long-Range Drive to Attain World Hegemony and The Role of Terrorism Therein," by Durbrow, outline, 1981 (Box 64)
- "Soviet Perceptions of Peaceful Coexistence: An Introductory Overview" by Foy D. Kohler, 1972 (Box 64)
- "Comments on the International Policy of the Soviet Union in the Second Year of Peace," by Durbrow, photocopy, 1947 (Box 64)
- Drafts by Durbrow
  - "The Unseen Revolution," by Durbrow, undated (Box 64)
  - "Suggestions on the Moscow Summit," by Durbrow, 1972 (Box 64)
  - "Objection: The Strategic Arms Limitation Agreement," by Durbrow, 1972 (Box 64)
  - "Implementation of the 1969 'Popular Unity' Formula in Iceland, Norway, France, Italy and Spain," by Durbrow, undated (Box 64)
  - "NATO-Near East: Same Crisis," by Durbrow, undated (Box 64)
  - "How to Gain Control of a Country," by Durbrow, undated (Box 64)
  - "Center Left-Wing Coalition Governments?" by Durbrow, 1981 (Box 64)
  - "The Declaration of Renewed Cold War," by Durbrow, 1969 (Box 64)
  - "Programs and Techniques of Wars of National Liberation," Durbrow, 1985 (Box 64)
  - "Plight of Our Vietnam Friends," Durbrow, undated (Box 64)
- Clippings, circa 1966-1967, 1972, 1980, 1985 (Box 65)
- Correspondence, 1965-1968, 1981, 1985, undated. (Box 65)
- Memoranda, 1967, undated (Box 65)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1960, 1967, 1969, 1977, 1982, 1985-1986, undated (Box 65)
- U.S. government reports, 1944, 1987 (Box 65)
- International press summaries, 1956, 1973, 1979, 1981, 1986 (Box 65)
- "Star Wars" Delusions and Dangers, 1985 (Box 65)
- The Diplomacy of Southeast Asia, excerpt, undated (Box 65)
- Cable between Great Britian's War Office and British Mission Bucharest, undated (Box 65)
- Durbrow oral history conducted by John T. Mason Jr., transcripts, 1981 (Box 65)
  For the Columbia University Oral History project
- Drafts by Durbrow (Box 65)
  - "Soviet Approaches to Mexico: Objectives and Implications,", undated (Box 65)
  - "Gorbachev's 'Demoratization' and 'Free Enterprise' Blitz,", 1987 (Box 65)
  - "Moscow Marines ? A Blessing!", 1987 (Box 65)
  - 20th Century's Fortunate Failure ? Leninism, 1989 (Box 65)
  - Gorbachev's 'Successful' Party Conference. Prospects?", 1988 (Box 65)
  - Gorbachev's Big Gamble Butter and/or Guns?, 1988 (Box 65)
  - Nicaragua - Another Soviet War of National Liberation, 1988 (Box 65)
  - Can Gorbachev Pull It Off? Prospects, 1988 (Box 65)
- "The Third Rome: The Rise of the New Civilization," by Constantin Melnik, outline, undated (Box 65)
- "A Conflict Situation" chapter 10 of memoirs, draft, undated (Box 65)
- "Disinformation at Work," by Durbrow, undated (Box 65)
- "Soviet Methods of Operation in Their Long-Range Drive to Attain World Hegemony and the Role of Terrorism Therein," by Durbrow, outline, 1981 (Box 65)
- "The Real Stalin Revealed," by Durbrow, undated (Box 65)
- "Saga of The Rise and Fall of Leninism: A Short Analysis," by Durbrow, 1989 (Box 65)
- "Short Analysis of the Rise and Fall of Leninism," by Durbrow, 1990 (Box 65)
- Clippings, 1975, 1985-1987 (Box 66)
- Correspondence, 1987 (Box 66)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1978, 1985, 1987-1988 (Box 66)
- Firing Line on "Sovietology" with guests William Hyland and Richard Pipes, transcript, July 8, 1987 (Box 66)
- "How to Hunt Relatives in Ticino or A Delightful Visit to Coglio with Bee's Relatives" by Durbrow, undated (Box 66)
- "The West Has Lost Its Courage," by Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn, photocopy, 1978 (Box 66)
- Clippings, 1987-1989, 1991 (Box 67)
- Correspondence, 1978 (Box 67)
- U.S. government reports and press releases, 1948 (Box 67)
- Mailgram photocopy, 1978 (Box 67)
- "Hot War, Cold War, and Détente - All Pay Well For the Kremlin," by Durbrow, undated (Box 67)
- Speech outlines and drafts by Durbrow, 1948-1951, 1956 (Box 67)
  - Soviet Objectives, 1949 (Box 67)
  - The Strategy of Political Action in Conflict, 1951 (Box 67)
  - U.S. Foreign Policy, 1949 (Box 67)
  - Objectives of Soviet Policies and Soviet Propaganda Techniques, 1949 (Box 67)
  - Soviet Foreign Policy, 1951 (Box 67)
  - Soviet Negotiation and Propaganda Tactics in the Cold War, 1949 (Box 67)
  - Soviet Propaganda and Objectives of Soviet Policies, undated (Box 67)
  - Objectives of Soviet Policies, 1948 (Box 67)
  - Economic Justice through Free Enterprise, 1956 (Box 67)
  - The United States of America and the Free World, 1956 (Box 67)
  - The U.S. Policy Vis-ï¿½-vis The Soviet Union, 1949 (Box 67)
  - U.S. Soviet Relations, 1950 (Box 67)
  - Ultimate Objectives of Communism and Its Potential Impact on the United States, 1950 (Box 67)
  - Formulation of U.S. Foreign Policy, 1950 (Box 67)
  - Soviet Political Objectives and Tactics, 1949 (Box 67)
  - Government Organization in the U.S.S.R. and Satellite States, 1949 (Box 67)
- Correspondence, 1949, 1961, 1985 (Box 68)
- Memorandum, 1949 (Box 68)
- Printed material photocopy, 1978 (Box 68)
- Petition of order requiring the Communist Party of the USA to adhere to the Internal Security Act of 1950 (Box 68)
- Durbrow oral history conducted by John T. Mason Jr., transcripts, 1981 (Box 68)
- Durbrow oral history conducted by David Mabon for inclusion in the Foreign Relations of the United States, 1958-1960, Volume 1, Vietnam, photocopy, 1984 (Box 68)
- Speeches by Durbrow, 1957, 1960-1962 (Box 68)
  - Inauguration of Saigon ? Bien Hoa Highway, 1957 (Box 68)
  - Orientation talk, 1961 (Box 68)
  - Speech at the American Community School Graduation, 1961 (Box 68)
  - Speech for 'Pre-Departure Orientation of Vietnamese grantees,'", 1960 (Box 68)
  - Address at J.D.P.V. Training School graduation, 1960 (Box 68)
  - Remarks to students of SciencesPo, 1962 (Box 68)
  - Address Given to Saigon Lions Club, 1961 (Box 68)
  - Speech at the Dedication Ceremony for the Saigon ? Bien Hoa Highway, 1961 (Box 68)
  - Address Delivered at Independence Palace in Vietnam, 1961 (Box 68)
- Speech outlines and drafts by Durbrow, 1957, 1961, 1965 (Box 68)
  - Notes for World Affairs Council Talk, 1961 (Box 68)
  - Ceremonies at Patton-Town of Ettelbruck, 1965 (Box 68)
  - Orientation Talk, 1961 (Box 68)
  - American Club Luncheon in Paris, 1961 (Box 68)
  - Arrival to Saigon, 1957 (Box 68)
- "Why Did Eisenhower Not Liberate and Hold Berlin?" by Durbrow, 1971 (Box 68)
- Correspondence, 1972, 1976-1977, 1979, 1981-1983, 1986, 1990, undated (Box 69)
- Clippings, 1970, 1972-1973, 1979, 1983,1986, 1990, undated. (Box 69)
- International press summaries, 1972 (Box 69)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1963, 1968-1969, 1972, 1976, 1980, 1985-1988-1990 (Box 69)
- 3 1/2 inch backup diskette, undated (Box 69)
- U.S. government reports, undated (Box 69)
- Miscellaneous excerpts, 1954-1955, 1958-1961, 1966-1968. (Box 69)
  Includes excerpts from Presidents Eisenhower and Johnson
- Durbrow speech delivered to the Air Command and Staff College Allied Officers Graduation Ceremony, 1972 (Box 69)
- New Russia journal, 1939 (Box 69)
- N. Scott Miler's testimony before the Senate Select Committee on Intelligence, undated (Box 69)
- Meet the Press with guest Prime Minister Lee Kuan Yew, transcript, 1967 (Box 69)
- Washington Report of the Air broadcasts, 1972-1973 (Box 69)
  - "Soviets Still Determined for World Socialism,", 1972 (Box 69)
  - "The Sihanouk Secret," with Durbrow, 1973 (Box 69)
- Drafts by Durbrow, 1985, undated (Box 69)
  - "Disinformation at Work,", circa 1985 (Box 69)
  - "Laos and Vietnam - The Same War,", undated (Box 69)
- "The Strange Alliance: The Story of Our Efforts at Wartime Co-operation with Russia," by John R. Deane, excerpts, undated (Box 69)
- "Soviet Perceptions of Peaceful Coexistence: An Introductory Overview," by Foy D. Kohler, undated (Box 69)
- "Peaceful Coexistence: The Cold War's New Nam," by Durbrow, 1972 (Box 69)
- "Communist Conquest in Latin America," by Herminio Portell-Vila, undated (Box 69)
- "Systems in Conflict," by Col. Raymond S. Sleeper, undated (Box 69)
- "The Fall of South Vietnam," by Bui Diem, undated (Box 69)
- "The Singapore Christmas Gift," by Sterling J. Cottrell, circa 1976 (Box 69)
- "Comments on the International Policy of the Soviet Union in the Second Year of Peace," by Durbrow, 1947 (Box 69)
- "Legal Issues in the Central American Conflict," by John Norton Moore, 1984 (Box 69)
- "How to Lose a War: Reflections of a Foreign Correspondent," by Robert Elegant, undated (Box 69)
- "Peaceful Coexistence: Russian, Chinese, and American Styles," by Earl L. Packer, circa 1972 (Box 69)
- Clippings, 1970-1972, 1979, 1989 (Box 70)
- Correspondence, 1969-1972, 1976-1977, 1980, 1987, 1992, undated. (Box 70)
  Includes photocopies and letters with Spiro Agnew, William F. Buckley, Jr., and Clare Booth Luce.
- Printed material and photocopies, 1969, 1970, 1974, 1986-1991 (Box 70)
- U.S. government reports, 1949, 1970-1973, 1987 (Box 70)
- Khrushchev's main document adopted by the International meeting of Communist and Worker's Parties in 1969 (Box 70)
- Durbrow biographical information, undated (Box 70)
- "America's Future Is at Stake in Vietnam," by DeWitt S. Snell, 1972 (Box 70)
- "Why Suddenly 'Peace for Our Time'?" by Durbrow, undated (Box 70)
- "Russia - Seven Years Later," by George Kennan, photocopy, 1944 (Box 70)
- "Famine in Ukraine: 1932-1933," by Bohdan Krawchenko, 1986 (Box 70)
- "Blind Eye to Murder: Britain, the United States and the Ukraine Famine of 1933," by Marco Carynnyk, undated (Box 70)
- "Program and Techniques of Wars of National Liberation," by Durbrow, 1985 (Box 70)
- Clippings, 1968, 1987-1988, undated (Box 71)
- Printed material, 1967, 1987-1988 (Box 71)
- Correspondence, 1936, 1938, 1944-1946, 1950, 1952-1953, 1955-1959, 1961-1967, 1970, 1981, 1985, 1987-1988, undated. (Box 71)
- Memoranda, 1987-1988 (Box 71)
- U.S. government reports, 1987-1988, undated. (Box 71)